在过去的视频中，我们学习了CPU的工作原理、如何读取汇编程序以及如何反转
engineer the functionality of a simple program.
在接下来的视频中，我想更深入地探讨我们如何利用
a program when we have the ability to corrupt memory.
This first video will be more about how to setup and get everything running.
So we can focus on the technical part in the next videos.
这个视频的标题是受著名的短语文章“粉碎堆栈”的启发
For Fun And Profit” from 1996.
You can imagine that a lot of stuff has changed since then.
Though, we first have to learn about the basics, before we can have a look at modern techniques.
We will kind of follow the timeline of exploitation technique discovery and attempted mitigations.
Like DEP or ASLR, just to name two.
作为接下来几段视频的基础，我将使用Linux中包含的挑战
images provided by exploit-exercises.com.
This allows you to set up this system as well, which I highly recommend.
使用ProtoStar，您将从简单的内存损坏和修改开始，函数
redirection, and finally executing custom shellcode.
为了尽可能容易地引入ASLR和非可执行内存
has been disabled.
So first download the protostar .iso and boot from it in the VMWare Player.
正如你所看到的，它并不像我们的Ubuntu系统那样从一个良好的图形用户界面开始。
does.
But don’t panic, you learned how to use the command-line from the very first episode.
现在，我将利用这个时刻向您介绍“ssh”，它代表安全shell和
是一个允许我们通过网络连接到系统的程序，它有一个ssh服务器
running.
当您必须管理运行的服务器时，这将是您获得的访问权限。
for example a website.
这就是我在第一集就把你介绍给指挥部的原因，
because you really really have to know how to use it.
You can also tell that I run windows as a host OS.
我想我以前没提过，但主要原因是，我认为
majority of people start out on Windows, which means it’s the best way to reach more people.
We don’t want to be excluding like so many other parts of our societies.
At least for me, hacking conveys a spirit to be open and share knowledge.
这就是为什么我现在必须下载Putty for Windows，它是Windows客户端
ssh.
To use it to connect to this machine we have to find the IP address of it.
The username and password for the protostar image is just “user”.
So use that to login.
然后执行命令“ip addr”，找到分配的IP，然后将其复制到
putty, save this session and press Open.
You have to login again, but this is much better now.
We can copy data back and forth and we can have multiple connections.
The equivalent for Mac and Linux is just simply `ssh`, the username “user” at the ip address.
Ok.
At the moment our shell is /bin/sh.
And as you can see, tab-completion doesn’t work.
But we can execute `/bin/bash` instead, which makes the command-line a bit nicer.
So what do we have here.
有了uname-a，我们可以获得一些系统信息，并且可以看到我们有一个32位的Linux
with a 2.6.32 kernel.
So how does this work now.
On the website it says: The levels to be exploited can be found in the /opt/protostar/bin directory.
Let’s have a look.
`Ls` to list all files in this directory.
Immediately you will notice this weird red background color for the filenames.
Let’s have a closer look.
使用“files”，我们可以检查文件类型，它告诉我们它是setuid elf 32位
executable.
From earlier videos you may remember that we have never encountered `setuid` before.
As always, if we want to know something in linux, we can look in the linux manual.
Though, the man page for setuid is actually about the setuid function provided by libc.
But that doesn’t bother us, because it might be related.
So let’s see what it says here about this function.
setuid stands for set user identity.
And… setuid sets the effective user ID of the calling process.
mhh… with cat /etc/passwd we can see all users on this system.
Remember our user is called user so we have the id 1001.
And the root user has id 0.
这是否意味着，我们可以简单地以非特权用户的身份编写C程序并执行
将ID为0的setuid变为根？
Obviously not.
That would be horrible.
再往下讲，它告诉我们可能的错误，比如说，eperm说用户不是
privileged and the uid does not match the real uid of the calling process.
好的……那么……它能用来做什么？
一个示例用法是，根进程可能希望将特权删除到非特权
user, that in case the process gets exploited, the attacker does not gain root privileges.
所以，如果你有一个必须从根开始的过程，但不再需要它，
it’s good to drop them.
Anyway.
这与我们的setuid二进制有什么关系？
Let’s open a second ssh session to look at all running processes.
Now open a process that keeps running.
Something simple like a vim editor.
And then we can use the other shell to execute `ps aux` to list all running processes.
Now we have to search a bit, but here it is.
The first column tells us the user of the running process.
And because we as “user” have executed vim, it will run with our privileges.
So no let’s execute one of those setuid binaries and do the same.
Let’s search the program name.
Here it is.
但是你看到第一行了吗？
It says it’s running as root.
卧槽？
这怎么可能？
Let’s have a look again at the file permissions.
好的，首先，`r``dash``x`表示系统中的任何人都可以读取此文件，并且
execute it.
The next 3 permissions are the same and refer to the permissions for the group.
A group is just an id, that multiple users could share.
So we are in the group that is also called user.
But theoretically you could group multiple users together.
Ok.
Now it get’s interesting.
The first character indicates if a file is a directory.
Well it’s not.
So the remaining 3 permissions are for the owner of the file.
The owner of the file is root.
并且所有者有读、写和…的权限？
So the s replaced what should be x for executable.
This is called the setuid bit.
We have already looked at the running process, so you can guess what this does.
当设置了这个位，并且我作为一个普通用户执行它时，Linux将实际执行它。
with the privileges of the owner.
So in this case it will run as root.
为什么会有人这么做？
There are two good examples.
First, you may know sudo.
Which is a program that allows you to run something as root if you are a normal user.
那么，即使您输入了命令，sudo如何以根用户身份执行程序呢？
Well it also has the setuid bit.
Another great example is the ping program.
Ping will also run as root, because it has the setuid bit set.
你为什么要问？
Because ping wants to send an ICMP packet which is a fairly low layer.
And linux generally doesn’t allow normal users to create such raw packets.
但是，由于ping并不邪恶，有人创建了setuid二进制文件，允许普通用户
send ICMP packets.
如果有一个像ping这样的程序的漏洞可以让您执行
任意代码为根，对吗？
So it’s clear, that setuid can be really dangerous.
Well.
And that’s the whole point of the challenges from protostar.
If we can exploit one of these programs here, we can escalate privileges and gain root.
This is basically like jailbreaking on iPhones or rooting on android devices.
您试图找到一个漏洞，允许您在特权中执行任意代码。
mode.
嗯，在那些真正的设备上，尤其是iOS上，这是非常复杂的，而且
a lot more layers are involved, but now you get a better imagination of the whole thing.
One last thing before we start with the challenges.
你知道你可以调试程序，对吗？
For example you can use strace to spy on the system calls.
Or simply use gdb.
And gdb allows you to modify memory.
所以您可以在gdb中打开这个setuid二进制文件，修改代码并执行任何
你想要根？
let’s try it.
Ok it seems to run.
So let’s rerun it and look at the process list.
As you can see it doesn’t run as root anymore.
The reason is, that gdb could not debug a process that runs as another user.
So gdb actually forces the binary to NOT run as root so it can actually debug it.
So good idea, but unfortunately… or maybe fortunately it’s not that simple.
I guess we have to rely on good old exploiting techniques.
See you in the next video when we start with the first challenge.